Guide to the Harry Caplan papers, 1918-1980.
Harry Caplan papers, 1918-1980
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Harry Caplan papers, 1918-1980.
14-9-1921
Harry Caplan, 1896-
27.8 cubic ft.
Correspondence, manuscripts, papers, photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The bulk of this collection consists of letters from Caplan's colleagues, graduate students, friends, and family members, and notes and drafts of his replies. Also included are speeches and lectures, course materials, bibliographies, subject files, notes, manuscripts, reprints and other published material, diaries, photographs, sketches, materials concerning Cornell, and other papers reflecting Caplan's career as a classics professor.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Harry Caplan received his B.A. in 1916, M.A. in 1917, and Ph.D. in 1921 from Cornell. He taught in Cornell's Department of Public Speaking, 1919-1923, and in the Department of Classics, 1924-1980.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The bulk of this collection consists of letters from Caplan's colleagues, graduate students, friends, and family members, and notes and drafts of his replies. Also included are speeches and lectures, course materials, bibliographies, subject files, notes, manuscripts, reprints and other published material, diaries, photographs, sketches, materials concerning Cornell, and other papers reflecting Caplan's career as a classics professor.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Caplan, Harry, 1896-; Cornell University--Faculty.
Subjects:
Classical languages--Study and teaching.; Classical literature--Study and teaching.; College teachers.
Form and Genre Terms:
Diaries.; Photographs.; Sketches.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence, 1918-1939 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1920s-1945 (Box 2)
- Correspondence, 1942-1949 (Box 3)
- World War II letters from Jay (Caplan's nephew), 1943-1944 (Box 3)
- Correspondence, 1950-1956 (Box 4)
- Correspondence, 1956-1961 (Box 5)
- Correspondence, 1961-1964 (Box 6)
- Correspondence, 1965-1968 (Box 7)
- Correspondence, 1969-1973 (Box 8)
- Correspondence, 1974-1976 (Box 9)
- Correspondence, 1976-1980 and (Box 10)
- Unsorted correspondence (in envelopes), 1940-1954 (Box 11)
- Unsorted correspondence (in envelopes), 1954-1963 (Box 12)
- Unsorted correspondence (in envelopes), 1957-1969 (Box 13)
- Unsorted correspondence (in envelopes), 1960-1971 (Box 14)
- Unsorted correspondence (in envelopes), 1967-1973 (Box 15)
- Unsorted correspondence (in envelopes), 1969-1971 (Box 16)
- Unsorted correspondence (in envelopes), 1972-1975 (Box 17)
- Unsorted correspondence (in envelopes), 1964-1976 (Box 18)
- Unsorted correspondence (in envelopes), 1975-1979 (Box 19)
- Subject files (Box 20)
- Subject files (Box 21)
- Alphabetical files; miscellany; students' papers (Box 22)
- Writings (Box 23)
- Writings; diaries; appointment book (Box 24)
- American Philological Association, 1947-1953 (Box 25)
- Bibliography - Medieval and Renaissance Latin letter, 1946 (Box 25)
- Bibliography, 1948 (Box 25)
- American Academy in Rome letters, 1949; 1951 (Box 25)
- Jewish War Veterans, 1949 (Box 25)
- Certificate of Incorporation; The Statler Club (Box 25)
- India-Cornell memoranda (Box 25)
- Notes - slips, cards, etc. with notations and references (Box 25)
- Modus faciendi sermones (manuscript) (Box 25)
- Family Correspondence (Box 25)
  a. "Family 1"
  b. "Family 2"
  c. "Family 3"
  d. "Family 4"
  e. Bulletins of Congregation Beth Emeth
- Thesaurus Lingua Latina correspondence (Box 25)
- American Philolgocal Association paper and material, 1954 (Box 25)
- Abstracts by various authors (manuscripts) (Box 25)
- Miscellaneous (Box 25)
- Menander the Rhetorician (Box 25)
- Manuscript of Ad Herrenium (Box 26)
- "University Matters" - material concerning University meetings, recommendations for positions, etc. (Box 26)
- Committee on Educational Policy; minutes of the committee meeting, 1946-1947 (Box 26)
- Personal documents (Box 26)
- Linguistic Society financial report, 1946 (Box 26)
- Presentation of Caplan in Wales, ca. 1928-1929 (Box 26)
- Caplan's statement on his thesis, 1921 (Box 26)
- Photographs (Box 27)
- Sketches; prayer book (Box 28)
- Postcards, ca. 1949-1965 (Box 29)
- ADDN (Box 30-32)